A Guide to the Charles T. Loehr Collection, 1862-1943
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Charles T. Loehr Collection, 1862-1943
The Library of Virginia
51904
1 cubic foot (3 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Peter Alten, Manassas.
Biographical Information
Charles Theodore Loehr was born on 8 August 1842. He served in the First Virginia Infantry Regiment during the Civil War. Following the war, he was active in the Old First Virginia Association, and wrote War History of the Old First Virginia Infantry Regiment, Army of Northern Virginia in 1884. Loehr died on 5 March 1915 and is buried in Hollywood Cemetery in Richmond.
Scope and Content
Collection, 1862-1943, of Charles T. Loehr (1842-1915) of Richmond, Virginia, including booklets, brochures, buttons, invitations, photographs, programs, and ribbons relating to reunion activities of the First Virginia Regiment, the United Confederate Veterans, and other organizations.
Contents List
- Battle Flag and Wooden Pole (Small Souvenir), undated. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Button - United Sons Confederate Veterans Third Reunion, Atlanta, Ga., 20-23 July 1898. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Button - Grand Camp Confederate Veterans, Battle of the Crater, July 30th, 1864, Petersburg, Va., 23-25 October 1901. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Button - C.S.A., undated. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Centennial Kissing Card Protector. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The City on the James, Andrew Hammond, ed., 1893. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Confederate Memorial Service Program, 21 June 1922. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Dickinson, Elizabeth B. Loehr - Letter, undated. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Field Infirmary Pass (Blank). (Box 1, Folder 5)
- First Virginia Infantry Flag - History, 1929. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The First Virginia Regiment - An Historical Sketch - Compiled by Charles A. Crawford, 1916. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- First Virginia Regiment Reunion Invitation, 18 July 1911. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Hill Monument Unveiling Souvenir Booklet, 30 May 1892. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Guide to Richmond and the Battle-Fields by W.D. Chesterman, 1881. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Lee Camp Soldiers' Home - Reports of the Board of Visitors, 1910-1911. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Medal - Veteran, U.C.V, Richmond, Va., 1907. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Opening Celebration of the 1st Virginia Regiment Armory - Friday, May 29, 1914. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Our Flags" - Souvenir of Solid South Booth, Confederate Bazaar, April 1903. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Photograph - Virginia State Capitol Building, ca. 1890-1900. (Box 3, Folder n/a)
- George E. Pickett Camp - By-Laws and Rules of Order, 1889. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Postcard - First Virginia Infantry Company D. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Reunion Photograph - Pickett's Monument, Hollywood Cemetery, Richmond, Va. (3 photographs, different views), 5 Octber 1888. (Box 3, Folder n/a)
- Reunion Photograph - unknown location, 19 July 1897. (Box 3, Folder n/a)
- Reunion Photograph - Spangler's Spring, Gettysburg, Pa., ca. 1890-1900. (Box 3, Folder n/a)
- Reunion Photograph - unknown location, ca. 1890-1900. (Box 3, Folder n/a)
- Reunion Photograph - 40th Anniversary Old First Virginia Infantry Regiment, 18 July 1901. (Box 3, Folder n/a)
- Reunion Photograph - Old First Virginia Infantry Regiment, 1901. (Box 3, Folder n/a)
- Reunion Photograph - Louisa, Va., 17 August 1905. (Box 3, Folder n/a)
- Reunion Photograph - Old First Virginia Infantry Regiment, July 1906. (Box 3, Folder n/a)
- Reunion Photograph - Gettysburg, Pa., 15 September 1906. (Box 3, Folder n/a)
- Ribbon - R.E.Lee Camp No. 1, C.V. Richmond, Va., Jacksonville, Fl., 6-8 May 1874. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Ribbon - "I Helped Haul the R.E. Lee Statue From Elba Station to the Monument Site," Wednesday, 7 May 1880. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Ribbon - Pickett Camp, C.V., Reunion, Louisa Camp, C.V.,9 August 1894. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Ribbon - C.V. Re-Union, 1895. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Ribbon - George E. Pickett Camp, C.V., Louisa Camp Re-Union, 16 August 1895. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Ribbon - Sixth Annual Reunion, C.V., and Laying Corner Stone of Monument to President Jefferson Davis, at Richmond, Va., 30 June - 2 July 1896. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Ribbon - Delegate Grand Camp C.V. of Va., Richmond, Va., 20-22 October 1897. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Ribbon - Pickett Camp, Ladies' Auxiliary, Richmond, Va., undated. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ribbon and Button - U.C.V. Reunion, Atlanta, Ga., Picketts Men, 20-23 July 1898. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Ribbon and Button - U.C.V. Veteran, Newport News, Virginia, 1903. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Ribbon and Button - C.S.A. Delegate 16th Annual Reunion Gr. Camp Confederate Veterans of Virginia, Newport News, 1903. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Ribbon and Button - Ladies' Auxiliary of Pickett Camp, C.V., Richmond, Va., undated. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Ribbon and Button - Unveiling Winnie Davis Monument, undated. (Box 2, Folder n/a)
- Richmond - The Pride of Virginia: An Historical City, 1900. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- St. John's Evangelical Church (Richmond VA) Dedication Program, 19 February 1928. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- St. John's Messenger, Vol. XXVIII No. 11 (September 1943). (Box 1, Folder 18)
- United Confederate Veterans 6th Annual Reunion Memorial Booklet, 1896. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- United Confederate Veterans Reunion Invitation, 30 May - 3 June 1907. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- United Confederate Veterans - 17th Annual Reunion - Report of the General Chairman, 1907. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- United Confederate Veterans 25th Reunion Souvenir Booklet, 1-3 June 1915. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- United States Farmers Almanac, 1862. (Box 1, Folder 23)